[音乐]
[Music]
没有什么语言可以
no words can make feelings as palpable
像温柔的抚摸一样让感情触手可及
as a gentle touch
但抚摸也可以减轻疼痛
but a touch can also relieve pain
增强我们的免疫系统
strengthen our immune system
甚至让我们活得更久
and even make us live longer
[音乐]
[Music]
长期以来主要被科学忽视的
long mainly ignored by science
温柔抚摸终于得到
gentle touch is finally getting the
重视 值得
attention it deserves
[音乐]
[Music]
触摸是最基本的，我想说它
touch is a fundamental i would say it's
是绝对必要的，就像
an absolute necessity as much as the air
我们呼吸的空气和我们吃的食物一样
we breathe and the food that we eat
它可以让你的整个世界平静下来，它可以
and it can calm your whole world it can
让你的身体感觉更好，你的
make your body feel better you become
压力会减轻
less stressed
[音乐]
[Music]
触摸 刺激
touching stimuli change the biochemistry
以戏剧性和积极的方式改变我们大脑的生物化学
of our brain in a dramatic and positive
way
现在我们不能那么做我们
and now we can't do it as much we start
开始注意到它是多么重要
to notice how incredibly important it is
[音乐]
[Music]
第一次触摸
the first touch
[音乐]
[Music]
我们生活中最重要的时刻之一
one of the most important moments in our
lives
这个婴儿的视力还不能超过 30
this baby cannot see further than 30
厘米
centimeters yet
我们的听觉
and our sense of hearing does not fully
直到我们 4 周大时才完全发育
develop until we are four weeks old
[音乐]
[Music]
我们首先通过触觉体验世界，
we first experience the world through
touch
我们似乎非常依赖我们
it seems we're so reliant on our sense
的触觉 它甚至对
of touch that it is even essential to
我们的生存至关重要，我们离不开它，
our survival we can't do without it
因为它是我们与环境互动的最简单方式
because it's the easiest way for us to
interact with our environment
[音乐]
[Music]
当婴儿哭泣时，它想感受
when a baby cries it wants to feel its
父母的抚摸
parents touch
如果没有它，言语还不足以抚慰
words are not yet enough to soothe it
它 子宫的温和压力
without the gentle pressure of the womb
婴儿通过
babies find a sense of security through
爱抚和体温找到安全感
caress and body heat
他们确信有人在那里
they are reassured that someone is there
并关心他们
and cares for them
抚摸
touching strengthens the bond between
从我们提到的第一刻起加强了孩子和父母之间的联系
child and parents from the very first
moment
是的我们人类被听到
we mentioned yeah we humans are heard
动物 这样我认为我们
animals in this way i think that we
实际上使用触摸来学习和
actually use touch to learn and feel
感觉我们现在是我们团队的一部分
that we are now part of our group
我们的社区也保护我们
and our community also protects us
我认为这
i think that this is especially
在生命的开始特别重要，因为
important at the beginning of life that
我们知道我们并不孤单，
we know we are not alone that there is
有人 谁会照顾我们，我们
someone who will take care of us and we
现在不知何故
now somehow belong to this community
与这些其他人属于这个社区
with these other people
我们作为人类需要关系
we as humans need relationships
没有人可以独自存在
no one can exist on their own
我们进化到一起生活在一个小
we evolved to live together in a small
group
因为它为我们提供保护，免受自然灾害
because it offers us protection from the
和敌人的伤害
elements and our enemies
我们通过触摸表达归属感，
and we express belonging through touch
它让我们感到安全，亲近
it makes us feel secure close
给我们带来舒适或愉悦，
gives us comfort or pleasure
这是我们表达快乐和联系的方式
it is how we express joy and connection
[音乐]
[Music]
人类有一个高度差异
humans have a highly differentiated
化的感知和分类系统
system for perceiving and classifying
触摸
touch
因为触摸也可能意味着力量和
because a touch can also mean power and
暴力
violence
它可以
it can frighten and threaten us
在几分之一秒内吓坏和威胁我们
in fractions of a second the receptors
我们皮肤中的感受器告诉我们它是一种什么样的
in our skin tell us just what kind of
触摸
touch it is
[音乐]
[Music]
我们是否应该放松
whether we should relax
或采取行动以逃避危险
or spring to action to escape danger
识别 对触摸进行分类是
recognizing and classifying touch is the
我们学习的第一门语言
very first language we learn
科学直到最近才开始
science has only recently begun to
研究这种语言到底有多微妙和细微差别
research how subtle and nuanced this
language really is
Rebecca Buma 和她在
rebecca buma and her colleague in ling
瑞典 ling cooping 的同事正在研究
cooping sweden are investigating the
触摸在我们的交流中扮演的角色
role that touch plays in our
communication
这个现在看看这个 是的，
this one now look at this yeah just how
它在表达我们的情感方面有多好
good is it at expressing our emotions
两个测试对象看不到对方
the two test subjects cannot see each
other
他们试图传达不同的信息
they try to convey different messages by
只需用他们的手臂或手就可以表达
just using their arm or hand
我爱你
i love you
我很难过
i'm sad
当心
watch out
电极记录面部肌肉的最轻微
electrodes register the slightest
运动一种
movements of the facial muscles an
客观的方法来测量情绪
objective method to measure emotions
[音乐]
[Music]
她应该
the information she is supposed to
传达给他的信息出现在屏幕上
communicate to him appears on a screen
他 可以识别她的
and he can recognize her messages
信息当然你也可以尝试
of course you can also try to convey
用语言来表达情感
emotions with words
但我认为
but i think what comes across and what
你所感受到的和你真正感受到的是另外一回事
you actually feel is something else
如果我对
it's entirely different if i say to
某人说嘿我爱你
someone hey i love you
或者如果我通过触摸
or if i show it by touching
拥抱亲吻来表达它是完全不同的 或
hugging kissing or cuddling with them
最重要的是与他们拥抱 我们
above all we are better able to convey
通过触摸比通过语言更能表达爱和同情
love and compassion through touch than
面部表情或
through words facial expressions or
手势
gestures
触摸创造了更深层次的情感
touch creates a much deeper emotional
联系
connection
我们现在必须保持距离这一事实如何
how has the fact that we now have to
影响了我们和我们的
keep our distance affected us and our
relationships
关系 制造障碍 它
it just creates barriers it creates
在人与人之间制造障碍 所以如果你
barriers between people and so if you
无法伸出手去触摸某人
cannot reach out and touch someone
这意味着你缺乏
it means you lack that
与他们的互动并且
interaction with them and
这意味着我们无法加强我们的
it means that we can't reinforce our
社会纽带，
social bonds and this is especially true
目前对于正在
at the moment for younger people who are
学习如何互动的年轻人尤其如此
learning how to interact
因此在正常世界中，我们会
and so in a normal world we would shake
握手、拥抱或亲吻，尤其是孩子
hands or hug or kiss especially children
现在我们必须告诉他们 他们 不 不 你
and now we have to tell them no no you
不能这样
can't do it
做 所以它不仅会影响
and so not only does it have an impact
我们目前建立的社会关系
on social relationships that we make for
而且它可能
the moment but it could have bigger
implications for the future as well
对未来产生更大的影响
just reaching your hand out to another
person creates a kind of relationship
与他们的关系，
with them
但这是如何发生的
but how does that happen
这是
this is one of the questions that
神经科学家罗谢尔·阿克利正在
neuroscientist rochelle ackerly is
前马赛大学研究的问题之一，
investigating at the university of ex
marseille
尽管大流行迫使
although the pandemic has forced her to
她暂停了她的研究，但她的
take a break from her research her
发现引起了越来越大的
findings are generating an ever greater
兴趣，
interest
因为许多 我们敏锐地
because many of us are acutely aware of
意识到我们现在生活中缺少的东西
what we are missing in our lives right
now
温柔的触摸既可以使人平静也可以
gentle touch can be both calming it can
让人放松 但它也是
be relaxing but it's also something that
我们需要的东西 它对我们来说是必不可少的 r life because
we need it's essential for life because
if we didn't have reward in touch 如果我们
if we didn't have reward in touch if we
觉得它不愉快，我们就不
didn't find it pleasurable we wouldn't
会这样做，如果我们不这样做，我们就不会
do it and if we didn't do it we wouldn't
在这里
be here
[音乐]
[Music]
触摸在开始时尤为重要
touch is especially important at the
beginning of life
出生后的生命 它通过接触稳定呼吸
after birth it stabilizes breathing body
体温甚至血糖水平
temperature and even blood sugar levels
婴儿感知他们的
through contact babies sense their
身体边界
physical boundaries
帮助他们了解
that helps them to learn the difference
自己与他人之间的差异
between themselves and others
这对于某些
it is essential for certain
发育里程碑至关重要
developmental milestones
然后您仍然可以看到
and then you can still see the effects
它的影响甚至 10 年后，
of it even 10 years later that there are
cognitive differences between babies who
经历过大量触碰的
had experienced a lot of touch and those
婴儿与经历过
who had experienced very little
很少基本生理需求的婴儿之间存在认知差异
a basic biological need
但多年来
and yet for many years cuddling stroking
and hugging children was frowned upon
直到 1950 年代和 60 年代，拥抱
as late as the 1950s and 1960s physical
抚摸和拥抱孩子的行为都不被接受。 被认为是不必要的，
closeness was considered unnecessary or
甚至是有害的，
even harmful
但研究和经验已经改变
but research and experience has changed
了这一切，
all this
尤其是在我们最亲近的亲戚中
especially among our closest relatives
[音乐]
[Music]
他们显然恶魔 想一想
they clearly demonstrate what happens
当新生儿没有
when newborns do not experience
亲近和
closeness and
触摸时会发生什么 如果动物
touch if animals only received basic
在出生后几个月只接受基本护理 许多动物
care for months after birth many of them
死亡
died
幸存者遭受
and those that survived suffered
无法弥补的心理和身体
irreparable psychological and physical
伤害
damage
他们表现出身体发育迟缓
they showed reduced body growth
免疫系统不发达
underdeveloped immune systems and an
甚至无法执行 最简单的
inability to perform even the simplest
记忆功能
memory functions
大脑的中枢区域受损
central areas in the brain were impaired
并显示音量降低
and showed reduced volume
[音乐]
[Music]
因为触摸
because touch has a very direct effect
对我们的大脑
on our brains
有非常直接的影响，所以我们必须培养一种
it is essential for us to develop a
自我身体接触的感觉，这会
sense of self
启动重要的
physical contact sets important
发育过程
developmental processes in motion and
并刺激
also stimulates
生长 当婴儿被触摸
growth when a baby is touched millions
时，皮肤中的数百万个受体会发生反应并
of receptors in the skin react and
产生非常小的电流，
produce very small currents
这些微电流
these microcurrents reach different
通过密集的神经纤维网络到达大脑的不同区域，
regions of the brain via a dense network
of nerve fibers
当电脉冲
when the electrical impulses connect
与专门的神经细胞连接时，它们的
with specialized nerve cells there their
记忆门打开
memory gates open
信号分子被释放
signal molecules are released
他们触发增长促进
they trigger growth-promoting processes
直接在其他神经细胞中进行处理，或者
directly in the other nerve cells or
它们可以通过血液到达细胞并
they can reach cells via the blood and
trigger growth processes there
在饥荒中触发那里的生长过程
in the famine
这就是触摸总是
this is how touch always produces a
在整个身体中产生反应的方式
reaction throughout the body
它改变了我们的有机体
it changes our organism
我们不仅在婴儿而且在成人中都看到了这一点
we see this not only in babies but also
in adults
所以 我们不能忽视它，因为它
so we cannot ignore it because it
会影响我们生物学和
affects all aspects of our biology and
生理学
physiology
的方方面面 莱比锡触觉实验室的一项实验
an experiment in the leipzig haptics lab
记录了按摩前后的脑电波
brain waves are recorded before during
and after a massage
马丁·格伦瓦尔德 (martin grunvald)
martin grunvald has been interested in
自 1990 年代初以来就一直对轻柔的触感感兴趣，
gentle touch since the early 1990s
当时这个话题基本上还没有
back then the topic was basically still
科学界的未知领域
uncharted territory for the scientific
community
按摩如何改变大脑
how does a massage change brain activity
活动 脑电图测量显示脑
the eeg measurements show that brain
电波
waves slow down
减慢 结果是一种深度放松状态，
the result is a profound state of
类似于人在
relaxation similar to when a person is
熟睡时的状态
fast asleep
但是大脑不仅变得不那么
however the brain not only becomes less
活跃，
active
而且还释放出 当某些信使释放激素和神经递质时，信使
it also releases a cocktail of messenger
信号的混合物
signals
[音乐]
[Music]
when hormones and neurotransmitters are
化学物质通过血液
released certain messenger chemicals go
继续到达身体的其他部位，
on to reach the other areas of the body
through the bloodstream
这个过程导致
this process leads to among other things
肌肉松弛、
muscle relaxation a decrease in heart
心率下降和呼吸变浅，
rate and shallower breathing
这会导致一系列身体
there is a whole host of physical
变化，
changes
每次触摸都会在
every single touch literally goes under
我们的皮肤下发生
our skin
[音乐]
[Music]
我们经常忽略视觉或听觉
we often overlook visual or acoustic
刺激，
stimuli
但触摸绝不会如此，
but this is never the case with touch
因为识别某人的触摸并对其进行
because recognizing someone's touch and
分析对于我们
analyzing it is essential for our
survival
在毫秒内的生存至关重要我们的大脑
in a millisecond our brains can
可以确定触摸是否构成
determine whether or not a touch poses a
威胁
threat
我们皮肤中的数百万受体会做出反应
millions of receptors in our skin react
它们 记录压力振动热
they register pressure vibration heat
冷和疼痛
cold and pain
通过神经纤维传递信息
passing on the information via nerve
fibers
科学家们最近才发现了一种
scientists only recently discovered a
非常特殊的神经纤维，它
very special type of nerve fiber it
专门负责温和
specializes exclusively in gentle
愉快的触觉
pleasant touch
这些纤维不向我们提供
these fibers do not provide us with
有关我们外部世界的信息，
information about our external world
但它们能够记录 我们
but they are able to register whether we
是否喜欢触摸
liked the touch or not
这些所谓的海塔的发现
the discovery of these so-called sea
ctile afferents 可以深入了解
tactile afferents gives insight into
它对我们的社会生活到底有多大意义
exactly how significant it touches for
our social lives
francis mcglone 是最著名的
francis mcglone is one of the best known
研究人员之一，当谈到这些
researchers when it comes to these
抚摸纤维时，
stroking fibers
这一发现让他
this discovery filled him with
兴奋不已
excitement
[音乐
[Music]
] 我还记得
and i can remember the moment
我读论文的那一刻 据
i was reading a paper by what i would
我所知，我在神经科学领域的一位英雄，
say my one of my heroes in neuroscience
aqua valbo 教授
a professor aqua valbo
和 orca valvo 教授在这篇论文中
and orca valvo in this paper had
发现了人类皮肤中的一种神经纤维，
discovered a nerve fiber in the skin of
humans
称为 c 触觉传入神经，它对
called the c tactile afferent that
轻柔的触摸做出反应，当我
responded to gentle touch and when i was
阅读那篇论文时，我 在
reading that paper i was on a aeroplane
从华盛顿起飞的飞机
flying out of washington i could see
上，我可以透过窗户看到华盛顿纪念馆
washington memorial on my through my
我正在阅读那篇论文
window and i was reading that paper and
就在那一刻，一分钱掉了下来，我
i just at that moment a penny dropped i
想我确切地知道神经
thought i know exactly what that nerve
纤维从 1995 年开始对什么做出基本反应
fiber is basically responding to from
或 96，从那时起，
that was 1995 or 96 and since then
我很幸运地
i've been fortunate enough to
追求我的热情，描述和
pursue my passion in characterizing and
理解这个 nerdfighter
understanding just what this nerdfighter
所做的事情以及
does and how vital it is
它对我们的世界有多重要 幸福
to our well-being
这一发现导致了一种
this finding led to the discovery of a
全新的感觉系统的发现，
totally new sensory system
当我们被轻轻触摸时
when we are gently touched information
有关触摸类型和位置的信息会
about the type and location of the touch
在几毫秒内发送到大脑，
is sent to the brain in a matter of
milliseconds
同时 c-触觉传入神经
at the same time c-tactile afferents
也会对其做出
also react
反应 信号仅在
their signals only reach the brain after
一到两秒后
one to two seconds
到达大脑，更准确地说是
to be more exact to areas of the brain
大脑负责处理
that are responsible for processing
积极情绪的区域我们如何看待
positive feelings how we think about
他人
others
和自我认知
and self-perception
我认为这是将社会群体粘合
i think it's what glues social groups
在一起的原因
together so this touch is playing a
在调节
fundamental role in in regulating
the the reward of
群体中社交接触的奖励方面发挥作用，当你们
social contact in groups and when you're
在一起时，你们更有能力
together you're far more able to deal
应对来自外部
with stresses from the outside
环境的压力，就像缺失的
environment it's like the missing
粒子一样，让
particle that's allowed us to understand
我们??了解社交大脑
just what the social brain
真正激发的是什么
really fuels off
就是这种触觉神经将
and that is this touch nerve that brings
所有东西聚集在一起
everything together
也许海触觉传入被
perhaps the sea tactile afferents were
发现这么晚是因为它们
discovered so late because they are
很难
difficult to find
找到迪斯科舞厅 如此巨大的规模需要
a discovery of this magnitude requires
真正的专家，比如在瑞典的 ling coop
real specialists like here in ling coop
in sweden
一根纸一样细的针穿过
a paper-thin needle pierces through the
皮肤进入手臂的神经，
skin into a nerve in the arm
问题是神经中有许多
the problem is that there are many
不同的纤维，它们
different fibers in the nerve which can
可以连接到非常不同的感受器，
be connected to very different receptors
所以 这是找到合适的问题，
so it's a matter of finding the right
one
但在纤维最终对轻柔的抚摸刺激做出反应
but what is the fiber reacting to
exactly
之前，纤维对针的准确反应是什么？
the needle is corrected until a fiber
finally responds to the gentle stroking
stimuli
这是一个耗时的过程，
it is a time-consuming procedure
通常需要数小时，
usually taking hours
但
but it pays off
研究人员最终可以确定
the researcher can finally determine to
what the sea tactile afferents respond
best
当您
when you press gently with low force
像这样以缓慢的抚摸速度用较小的力轻轻按压时，海洋触觉传入的反应最佳
with a slow stroking velocity like this
它们被调整为对皮肤上的这种抚摸做出最佳反应
they are tuned to respond optimally to
this kind of stroke over the skin
因此我们认为这些触觉
and so we think that these see tactile
纤维
fibers
给了我们一种积极的感觉 有效的
give us a sense of positive effective
触摸，所以它是令人愉快的触摸
touch and so it's pleasant touch
所以当我们抚摸皮肤时太快
and so when we if we stroke the skin too
fast
或
or too slowly
太慢都不是最佳的，但如果我们
it's not optimal but if we stroke it
轻柔地抚摸它 爱抚皮肤
like a gentle caress of the skin
可以最佳地激活这些纤维，
it optimally activates these fibers and
我们认为这就是您
we think that this is how you gain
从触摸中获得乐趣
pleasure out of touch
的方式所谓的抚摸机器人实验
the so-called stroking robot experiments
表明，
demonstrate this
它可以用于
it can be used to test different touches
以完全相同的方式在每个测试
in exactly the same way on each test
subject
对象上测试不同的触摸 通过 c 触觉传入接收到的信号
the more signals received via the c
越多，
tactile afferents the more pleasant the
测试对象感知到的触摸
test subjects perceive the touch
越愉快，效果在 34 摄氏度时最强，
the effect is strongest at 34 degrees
celsius
与我们的指尖温度相同
the same temperature as our fingertips
有趣的是
and interestingly there's more of these
nerve fibers here
背部的神经纤维比
on the back than there are in the
前臂的神经纤维多，
forearm
所以 为什么人们喜欢好好按摩他们的背部
so why do people like having their back
他们喜欢好好按摩他们的背部
massage well they like having their back
因为从进化的角度来说那里有更多的这些
massage because there's more of these
神经纤维
nerve fibers there
in evolutionary terms
为什么你要在背部井上放一个奖励触摸系统
why would you put a reward touch system
你不能回到你的
on the back well you can't get to your
背部去梳理它所以 你需要找
back to groom it so you need to get
其他人，另一个灵长类动物需要
somebody else another primate needs to
过来为你梳理背部
come along and groom your back
[音乐]
[Music]
另一个迹象表明触摸扮演着
another indication that touch plays a
社会角色
social role
[音乐]
[Music]
这种高度复杂的感受器
this highly complex system of receptors
和神经纤维系统将我们与
and nerve fibers connects us with our
环境和其他人联系起来，
environment and other people
但仅凭触觉传入并不能
but see tactile afferents alone cannot
解释为什么我们会觉得触觉如此愉快，
explain why we find touch so pleasant
因为同样的刺激——轻柔
because the same stimulus the gentle
的皮肤触觉
touch of the skin
会
can trigger completely different
根据情况和情况引发完全不同的反应
reactions depending on the situation and
谁在抚摸我们
who is touching us
[音乐]
[Music]
这就是为什么我们的大脑必须学习的第一件事
that's why the first thing our brain has
就是区分是我们还是
to learn is to distinguish whether we or
其他人在抚摸我们，
someone else is touching us
因为这会对我们的大脑产生巨大的影响
because that makes a huge difference to
our brain
[音乐]
[Music]
当我抚摸我的手臂时，我的大脑可以
when i stroke my arm my brain can sort
预测会发生
of predict what's going to happen how
什么 当我抚摸我的手臂时它会感觉如何
it's going to feel when i stroke my arm
而发生的事情是大脑随后
and what happens is that the brain then
屏蔽了这些信息
blocks out this information
所以就好像大脑抑制了
so it's as if the brain suppresses the
当我抚摸自己的手臂时发生的感觉
feeling that occurs when i stroke my own
arm
并且它通过知道来做到这一点 会发生什么
and it does that by knowing what's going
to happen
所以它实际上
and so it actually doesn't even matter
对我们来说并不重要，
to us
所以我们不会有意识地感知
so we don't consciously perceive the
触摸，
touches
但我们经常触摸自己
nevertheless we touch ourselves
constantly
mostly on the face
每天在脸上触摸 400 到 800 次
between 400 and 800 times a day
为什么
why
要回答这个问题 马丁·
to answer this question martin
格鲁恩瓦尔德 (martin gruenvald) 在莱比锡的研究小组
gruenvald's research group in leipzig
提出了一项有趣的研究，
came up with an intriguing study
该假设是如果这在
the hypothesis was if this is all just
生物学上来说是无关紧要的，如果这
biologically speaking irrelevant if this
是不必要的触摸，
is an unnecessary touch
那么大脑就会发生生理变化
then physiological changes in the brain
不会出现，
will not show up
但如果这是
but if this is a touch stimulus which is
在物理层面上对我们很重要的触摸刺激，
important for us on a physical level
那么大脑中应该有相应的
then there should be corresponding
神经生理学变化
neurophysiological changes in the brain
这正是我们
and this is exactly what we have shown
现在
now
所展示的，测试对象被赋予了
the test subjects are given the task to
感受不同模式的任务 在小盘子上
feel different patterns on small plates
记住结构并稍后记录下来
remember the structures and record them
later
他们不知道他们
they do not know that they are being
在这样做时正在被拍摄，
filmed while doing this
以便他们的脑电波可以
so that their brain waves can be
与他们的自我触摸同时进行评估
evaluated in parallel with their self
touching
当他们试图记住他们的
when they try to remember what they have
感受时 他们突然听到一些令人不安的声音
felt they suddenly hear some disturbing
noises
脑电图的噪音揭示了
the eeg reveals just how stressed the
测试对象的压力
test subjects are
[音乐]
[Music]
[掌声]
[Applause]
这让研究人员能够 第一次
this gives researchers their first
有机会在实验室环境中
chance to see in a laboratory setting
看到有机体如何以
how the organism regulates itself in
这种
this way
方式调节自己 烦人的声音扰乱了他们的
the annoying sounds disrupt their
注意力
concentration
存储在他们
all of the information stored in their
记忆中的所有信息都丢失了
memory gets lost
他们感到
they feel overwhelmed
不知所措 正是在这样的时刻
and it is exactly at such a moment that
经常发生自我触摸
self-touching frequently occurs
对脑电波的评估显示了
the evaluation of brain waves shows how
短触如何调节大脑活动，
short touch regulates brain activity
它会回到中等水平的
it goes back to a medium level of
唤醒
arousal
因此测试对象可以更好地
as a result the test subjects can better
专注于手头的任务
focus on the task at hand
我认为这是第一步
and i think that's the first step
但当涉及到
but when it comes to the processes
它背后的过程时
behind it
大脑的哪些部分会触发大脑的其他
which parts of the brain trigger other
区域，让你的手
areas in the brain to make your hands
触摸你的脸，
touch your face
这样你会感觉好些
so you can feel better
现在有点不清楚，
it's all a bit unclear
但
now but the question where does that
触摸自己的冲动从何而来的问题
impulse to touch ourselves come from
是一个非常有趣的哲学
is a very interesting philosophical
问题
question
触摸来自 外在并
touch comes from outside and works deep
在我们
within us
内心深处起作用它使我们保持情绪平衡
it keeps us emotionally balanced
[音乐
[Music]
] 然而
and yet
自我
self-touch
触摸不能代替另一个人的触摸
cannot replace the touch of another
person
[音乐]
[Music]
但为什么当我们被触摸时它会有所不同
but why is it different when we are
touched
[音乐
[Music]
] 为什么同样的刺激会
and why does the same stimulus trigger
在我们的大脑中引发如此多的不同反应，
so many different reactions in our brain
从最大的喜悦到
from the greatest feelings of joy to
深深的
deep aversion
厌恶例如爱抚可以安慰平静并降低
a caress can comfort calm and lower the
heart rate
心率 如果您最好的朋友处于
for example if your best friend is in
困境中
distress
并且爱抚也可以以不同的方式触发我们，
and a caress can also trigger us in
different ways
例如
for example
当我们恋爱时，
when we're in love
那么我们的脉搏就会上升
then our pulse rises
我们会被唤醒，
we're aroused
因为每一次触摸都会
because every single touch sends lots of
向我们的大脑发送大量不同的信息
different information to our brain
[音乐
[Music]
] 振动压力
for example vibration pressure the
触摸的持续时间所以触摸的
duration of touch so the qualities of
质量然后它也被
the touch but then it's also evaluated
评估所以它也是触摸如何让
and so it's also how did that touch make
我感觉我喜欢它
me feel did i like it
我想要更多的触摸所以
do i want more of the touch and so the
大脑实际上将所有这些信息放在一起
brain actually puts together all this
以 提供全面
information to deliver a whole a rounded
的触控体验
experience for touch
rebecca buma 正在调查精益合作中医学影像科学和可视化
rebecca buma is investigating exactly
中心的确切发生方式和地点，
how and where this happens at the center
for medical image science and
visualization in lean cooping
她希望今天能看到 不仅是
today she wants to see not only the
大脑，还有脊髓在工作
brain but also the spinal cord at work
她的理论脊髓
her theory the spinal cord might play a
在处理触摸
much bigger role in processing touch
刺激方面可能比以前认为的发挥更大的作用
stimuli than previously thought
我认为这特别令人
i think what is particularly exciting
兴奋的是我们现在
about this is that we are now focusing a
对大脑的关注有所减少
little less on the brain
很长一段时间，神经科学
for a very long time neuroscience
完全围绕
revolved exclusively around everything
着大脑中发生的一切，我们完全
happening in the brain and we completely
忽视了
disregarded the whole interaction
大脑与身体之间的整个相互作用以及身体的
between brain and body and the
生理学，在
physiology of the body
来自海洋触觉传入的信号
before the signals from the sea tactile
甚至到达大脑之前，它们必须
afferents even reach the brain they must
首先到达脊髓 在
first arrive in the spinal cord in the
背
dorsal horn
角，我被触摸的信息
here the information i am being touched
被传送到其他神经细胞，
is conveyed to other nerve cells
主要是中间神经元，它们传输和
mainly interneurons which transmit and
处理信息，
process the information
只有少数神经细胞然后将
only a few nerve cells then send
信息发送到
messages up to the brain
大脑这里有趣的是
what is interesting here is that the
脊髓中的中间神经元接收
interneurons in the spinal cord receive
来自大脑的信息
information from the brain
这可能会影响我们
and this could impact our perception of
对脊髓触觉的感知，具体取决于 关于
touch in the spinal cord depending on
我们所处的情况以及谁在
the situation we are in and who is
触摸我们
touching us
一切终于准备好进行 MRI
everything is finally ready for the mri
测量
measurements
the spinal cord activity also change
当受试者触摸自己或被触摸时，脊髓活动也会发生变化
when the subject touches himself or is
touched
[音乐
[Music]
] 大脑扫描显示，当
the brain scans show that when the
受试者触摸自己时，某些
subject touches himself activity in some
区域的活动 与静止状态相比显着减少
areas is significantly reduced compared
to the resting state
但当有人触摸我们时，情况就大不相同了
but it's quite a different story when
someone is touching us
许多大脑区域被明显激活，
many brain regions are clearly activated
尤其是我们识别
especially regions in which we recognize
the intentions thoughts and plans of
他人的意图和计划以及负责
others and which are responsible for
这种奖励感的区域
that feeling of reward
一个主要的区别
a major difference
它是否也出现在脊髓
does it also show up in the spinal cord
测量中
measurements alternating between the
大脑和脊髓之间的交替测量现在采取
brain and the spinal cord are now taken
哪个区域首先被激活
which area becomes activated first
以及它们如何相互影响
and how do they influence each other
所以如果触摸刺激
so if the touch stimuli enter the spinal
通过神经进入脊髓它已经
cord via the nerves it is already
在这里区分 在我和
differentiated here between me and
其他人之间
others
大脑知道我在抚摸自己，
the brain knows that i'm touching myself
也许那样我们就会少做事
maybe then we'll have less activation in
脊髓中的激活 大脑知道
the spinal cord the brain knows someone
有人在触摸我 也许如果是
else is touching me maybe if it is
我特别喜欢的人
someone i particularly like
那么这可能是大脑实际上
then it may be that the brain actually
增加了脊髓的活动
increases the activity in the spinal
所以我们现在对它的反应更加敏感
cord so that we react more sensitively
to it
来自许多人的数据
now the data from the many test subjects
必须对测试对象进行
must be evaluated
评估 结果可以帮助我们开发
the results could help us develop
治疗精神
innovative approaches to treating mental
疾病或开发新型
illnesses or developing new types of
prostheses
anyone who feels a pleasant touch wants
more of it
the reward system in our brain is
responsible for this
hormones are released
假肢的创新方法 自己的药物可以
the brain creates its own drugs so to
说
speak
是根据触摸的类型混合不同的鸡尾酒
mixing together a different cocktail
depending on the type of touch
[音乐]
[Music]
这些包括例如
these include for example
内啡肽
endorphins
即所谓的幸福激素，它
the so-called happiness hormones that
给我们带来高度
give us a high
还有催产素，
and also oxytocin
这种结合激素让我们感到
the bonding hormone that makes us feel
亲近和联系 other person
close and connected to the other person
[音乐]
[Music]
这解释了为什么拥抱
this explains why a hug can be so much
比言语 [音乐] 更令人欣慰，
more comforting than words
[Music]
因为催产素起着非常重要的作用 催产素
because oxytocin plays a very important
在我们如何形成社会纽带中起着重要作用，
role in how we form social bonds
它通常被称为拥抱
it is popularly known as the cuddle
荷尔蒙，与出生和
hormone and associated with birth and
性别有关
sex
[音乐]
[Music]
但对灵长类动物进行的研究表明
but studies carried out on primates show
催产素决定了我们所有的
that oxytocin determines all of our
长期社会纽带
long-term social bonds
无论我们是否有亲缘关系或
regardless of whether we are related or
有性兴趣
have sexual interests
灵长类动物之间的友谊
a friendship between primates is
主要是通过相互梳理毛发来表达的
expressed primarily through mutual
grooming
particularly high levels of oxytocin are
当两只动物还
released when the two animals also have
以其他方式彼此密切接触时，会释放出高水平的催产素
intense contact with each other in other
ways
[音乐]
[Music]
the closer the primates are to each
other the more touching positively
affects them
这在进化上是有意义的，因为
this makes evolutionary sense because
催产素加强了对
oxytocin strengthens the need for
亲密关系的需求并促进了适当的
closeness and promotes appropriate
社会行为
social behavior
而且不仅在那些
and not only in the one who is receiving
受到关爱的
loving attention
人身上，给予触摸的人也必须
somebody who's giving touch also has to
得到奖励，我认为这种奖励
be rewarded and that reward i think is
是社会关系
the building of the social relationship
的建立 我们与灵长类动物讨论梳理
that we discuss with primates grooming
您需要购买的另一只灵长类动物的
the back of another primate you need to
背部 如果发生这种关系，
build a relationship for that to happen
你会挠我的背，我会
you scratch my back i'll scratch yours
在基本层面上挠你的，这就是互惠
at a basic level and that's reciprocity
和人类行为
and human behavior
[Music]
being in love only deepens our desire to
be touched
[Music]
oxytocin not only ensures this
关系中的可靠性、
but also feelings of reliability
保真度和安全性
fidelity and security in a relationship
它甚至可以改善我们的健康
and it even improves our health
[音乐]
[Music]
还具有镇静和促进生长的
also has calming and growth inducing
作用
effects
它还会影响我们的免疫系统
it also influences our immune system
它确实是一种多才多艺且有用的
it really is a versatile and useful
激素物质
hormone substance
[音乐]
[Music]
长期升高的催产素
couples with long-term elevated oxytocin
水平 实际上他们活得更久
levels actually live longer
他们不易受到压力
they are less susceptible to stress
他们的血压更低 他们的疼痛
their blood pressure is lower their pain
耐受水平
tolerance level is higher
更高 他们甚至是更好的学习者
and they are even better learners
[音乐
[Music]
] 夫妻父母孩子
the more that couples parents children
和亲人接触得越多
and loved ones touch each other the more
loving they feel about the relationship
将我们联系在一起，
oxytocin binds us together
加深我们的归属感，
deepening our feeling of belonging
但这种结合激素也会
however the bonding hormone can also
产生副作用，
have side effects
催产素不仅会产生副作用 这些
oxytocin doesn't just have these
美妙的积极影响让你
wonderful positive effects making you
感觉与周围的每个人都很亲近，
feel close to everyone around you
否则你可以说我们应该
otherwise you could say that we should
给每个人注射催产素，这
give oxytocin to everyone and that will
会让我们彼此相爱，从而
make us all love each other which makes
形成一个没有冲突的社会，
for a conflict-free society
但催产素只是强化了这样一个事实
but oxytocin just reinforces the fact
即我们只 感觉与
that we only feel connected to the
我们已经很亲近的人有联系，
people we are already close to you
所以当涉及到我们认为
so when it comes to people who we feel
不属于我们群体的人时，
do not belong to our group
我们更加疏远
we are even more distanced
[音乐]
[Music]
催产素加强
oxytocin reinforces the feeling of
了必须保护我们的群体免受他人侵害的感觉
having to defend our group against
others
[音乐]
[Music]
什么 这是否意味着在这样的时代，
what does this mean in times like these
当我们应该保持
when we are supposed to keep our
距离，
distance
当我们应该将身体
when we are supposed to limit physical
接触限制在我们最内圈的
contact to our innermost circle
时候，到目前为止，我们只能推测，
so far we can only speculate
但有一件事是肯定的，
but one thing is for sure
这对我们
it is not good for us
不利，权利，身体接触绝对是
rights physical contact is absolutely
对我们物种的存在至关重要，
essential to the existence of our
species
如果它失踪太久
if it's missing for too long
就会发生身体上的伤害，最重要的是心理上的
physical and above all psychological
伤害
damage can occur
这是灵长类动物在进化过程中第一次拥有
this is the first time in evolution
我们被告知不要
that primates have been told not to
互相接触这是一个
touch each other it's a precedent that's
从未发生
never happened before
过的先例，
and the cost and consequences
我们不知道成本和后果我的意思是你看到
we don't know i mean you see the data of
心理健康数据
mental health
上升，
rising
尽管尚无确切数字
although the exact figures are not yet
健康保险公司已经
available health insurers have noticed
注意到作为社会 疏远措施
that as social distancing measures have
增加了，与心理
increased so too has mental
健康相关的病假
health-related sick leave
焦虑症抑郁症甚至
anxiety disorders depression and even
成瘾也增加
addictions
了我们中的很多人都在寻找
quite a few of us are looking for a
替代品来代替我们所
substitute to replace what we are
缺少的
missing
[音乐]
[Music]
现在大脑非常聪明，这
and brains are very clever now that
可能意味着要多喝水 更多
could mean eating more drinking more
是的
yeah
人们可能正在做的是找到一种
what people may be doing is finding a
替代品来替代那种不是
substitute for that reward that wasn't
通过轻柔触摸来调节的奖励，并不是
there mediated through gentle touch not
说他们一定意识到
that they were necessarily aware that
这是造成它的原因，但缺少一种
that was the cause of it but there's a
奖励状态，我需要
reward state missing i need to get back
找回感觉良好的状态 我要抽根烟 我
to feeling good i'll have a smoke i'll
要抽根烟 我要喝一杯 你
have a cigarette i'll have a drink you
知道我要一块奶油蛋糕
know i'll have a cream cake that's
possible
that these
我们现在看到的这些行为很可能
behaviors that we're seeing now may well
由于我们
be a consequence of the fact that we're
不再进行社交接触，
not socially touching anymore
bayata Dietsen 在 2020 年封锁之初发起了她自己的研究。
bayata dietsen launched her own study at
the beginning of the lockdown in 2020.
社交距离对我们有何影响我们
how does social distancing impact us
is there a direct connection between our
缺乏接触与我们的压力水平之间是否存在直接联系
lack of contact and our stress levels
我们说触摸可以
the whole thesis that we say touch can
缓冲的整个论文现在可以真正进行
buffer this could now really be
调查并且与
investigated and with a really relevant
stressor compared to laboratory stress
我们之前使用的实验室压力测试相比真正相关的压力源
tests that we used before
来自德国各地的 250 个家庭
250 households from all over germany
参与了研究
participated in the study
家庭单身所有年龄组
families singles all age groups
在开始之前所有测试对象都是
before starting all test subjects were
将唾液样本测试送到他们的家中
sent saliva sample tests to their homes
然后他们不得不在
then they had to answer questions on
不同的日子回答问题
different days
他们在手机上收到这些问题的短信
they received these questions as text
messages on their cell phone
你感到孤独吗 你感到
do you feel lonely
痛苦
are you in pain
你有身体接触
do you have physical contact
吗 你觉得答案有多紧张和压力
how nervous and stressed do you feel
然后
the answers were then directly related
与压力荷尔蒙直接相关，
to stress hormones
他们在回答这些问题时采集了唾液样本
they took saliva samples while they were
answering these questions
这 让我们有机
and this gave us the opportunity to
会将个人测量、
combine the individual measurements the
心理生物学信息与
psychobiological information with the
日常调查中的受试者信息结合起来
subject information in this everyday
survey
因为我们有相对
and because we had a relatively large
较多的测试对象，这反过来又
number of test subjects which in turn
产生了大量的测量，
produced a lot of measurements we can
然后我们可以继续将这些个人
then go on to compare these individual
测量与 彼此并
measurements with each other and achieve
取得统计上显着的结果，
a statistically significant result
所以我们不仅有这些平均值，他们报告每天有
so we don't just have these average
多少触摸或接近或
values how much touch or proximity or
社交接触，
social contact per day they report but
但我们每时每刻都有
we have it moment by moment
唾液样本现在冷却并
the saliva samples are now cooled and
存储在研究所评估
stored at the institute the evaluation
begins
开始 皮质醇水平
what are the cortisol levels like and
如何以及催产素水平有多高
how high are the oxytocin levels
假设是压力荷尔蒙
the assumption is that stress hormones
在经历愉快触摸的人中减少得更快
decrease more rapidly in people who
experience pleasant touch
这正是
and that is exactly what is so important
对我们如此重要的
for us
[音乐]，
[Music]
因为压力本身并不
because stress is not inherently harmful
对我们有害 身体
to our bodies
我们的进化史已经表明，
our evolutionary history already shows
this
在压力大的情况下，这通常是
in stressful situations it's usually a
生存问题
matter of survival
例如，当攻击迫在眉睫时
for example when an attack is imminent
身体会适应以闪电般的速度战斗或逃跑，
the body adapts to fight or flight at
lightning speed
它会激活心血管系统、
it activates the cardiovascular system
肺部和肌肉
lungs and muscles
同时免疫系统会启动
at the same time the immune system kicks
in
它会做好准备，以便能够
it prepares itself to be able to quickly
从任何即将发生的伤害中快速痊愈。
heal from any impending injury
our defense against individual pathogens
另一方面，我们对个别病原体或物质的防御会关闭
or substances on the other hand shuts
down
我们的自主神经系统，压力
our autonomic nervous system and stress
荷尔蒙负责这种
hormones are responsible for this
肾上腺素、去甲肾上腺素和皮质醇
adrenaline noradrenaline and cortisol
一旦情况得到处理
as soon as the situation has been dealt
这些激素水平就会再次下降
with these hormone levels drop again and
身心就会恢复
the mind and body can recover
愉快 触摸会显着减少
pleasant touches dramatically decrease
压力荷尔蒙，
stress hormones
从而完美地缓冲
making for a perfect buffer against
对我们的健康有害的永久性压力
permanent stress that is harmful to our
health and more
[音乐]
[Music]
记录
the sea tactile afferents that register
每一次温柔触摸的海洋触觉传入也会
every gentle touch could also influence
影响我们对急性疼痛的感知
how we perceive acute pain
[音乐]
[Music]
我们都做到了
we've all done it
当我们伤害自己时，我们会不自觉地
when we hurt ourselves we automatically
触摸和爱抚我们甚至没有触摸到的疼痛部位
touch and caress the painful area
想想看
we don't even think about it
科学说这很有意义
and science says that makes perfect
sense
研究表明，触摸
studies show that touch has a very
对我们有非常积极的影响，
positive influence on us
它甚至可以抑制急性疼痛
it can even inhibit acute pain
例如
for example
当测试对象面临
when test subjects are confronted with
电刺激或热刺激时
electrical stimuli or thermal stimuli
如热刺激和疼痛被
such as heat stimuli and pain is
触发为 结果
triggered as a result
然后触摸可以直接减轻他们的
then touch can directly alleviate their
疼痛反应
pain response
如果突然受伤
if something suddenly hurts the pain
皮肤中的疼痛传感器首先
sensors in the skin are the first to
发出警报
sound the alarm
[音乐]
[Music]
这些闪电般的神经纤维
these lightning speed nerve fibers
确保我们立即注意到受伤
ensure that we notice the injury
immediately
例如我们可以立即将
for example we can immediately pull our
手拉开 从热炉顶上同时
hand away from a hot stove top and
自动用手摩擦
automatically rub our hand over the
疼痛区域
painful area
但是
at the same time however the pain signal
is also sent out via the slower
c-tactile afferent
如果我们现在用手在疼痛
if we now rub our hand over the painful
区域上摩擦，也会通过较慢的 c 触觉传入发出疼痛信号，此时会发送积极的爱抚信号
area the positive caress signals are
sent at the same time
因此，同时我们的大脑同时接收到一个负
our brain therefore receives a negative
信号和一个正信号
and a positive signal simultaneously
当我们被抚摸时，会发生什么
and what happens is that when we are
ain 将信号向下发送
stroked the brain sends the signal down
到较低的处理水平，所以可能
to lower levels of processing so maybe
在丘脑中，或者可能已经在
in the thalamus or maybe already in the
脊髓中，并告诉那里的神经元，
spinal cord and tells the neurons there
好的，冷静下来，我们正在被抚摸，
okay calm down we are being stroked
这一切都很好，
it's all good
有人在那里，所以一切都
someone is there and so everything can
可以降低一个档次
be taken down a notch
[ 音乐]
[Music]
我们仍然不知道疼痛是如何
we still don't know exactly how pain is
缓解的，
relieved
但它确实有效
but it works
而且不仅可以缓解身体疼痛，
and not only for physical pain
触摸还可以比语言更有效地缓解情绪上的痛苦
touch also helps with emotional pain
often more effectively than words
[音乐]
[Music]
它
it communicates important information
在两个人之间传达重要信息，
between two people
它创造了一种深刻的情感联系
it creates a deep emotional connection
超越文字
that transcends words
[音乐
[Music]
] 然而，随着世界变得
and yet as the world becomes
越来越数字化，我们彼此之间的身体接触越来越少，
increasingly digitized we have less and
less physical contact with one another
而这种流行病只是进一步
and the pandemic has only further
加强
reinforced this tendency
了我们大多数人的这种趋势，
for most of us
not by choice
如果你看不到
if you don't see people
人，你可以 触摸它们，所以
in person you can't touch them and so i
我相信我们
i do believe that our interactions on
在互联网上的互动，例如
the internet and for example
在家工作的人的增加，
the rise of people working from home
确实减少了触摸的
it does decrease the amount of touch
次数 如果我们每天都收到，如果
that we receive on a daily basis and if
我们确实减少了触摸，它确实
we do have decreased touch it really
会影响我们今天的幸福感
could impact on our well-being
我们大多数人触摸我们的智能手机
today most of us touch our smartphones
或平板电脑的次数远远超过我们触摸其他
or tablets far more than we touch other
人的次数，
people
我们在
we are in constant contact across
数千英里
thousands of miles
之外不断联系，但仍然 非常孤独
but still very much alone
孤独已经成为一种普遍现象
loneliness has become a mass phenomenon
对我们的健康造成严重后果，
with serious consequences for our health
因为当我们独自一人并失去
because when we are on our own and lose
群体的保护时，
the protection of the group
身体会保持警觉
the body goes on alert
皮质醇水平上升
cortisol levels rise
心脏病发作的风险中风
and the risk of heart attacks strokes
和抑郁症随着聪明人的增加而增加
and depression increases with wise man
godzilla
哥斯拉，我们已经知道了吗，
does we know this already
感谢上帝，我们知道孤独会
thank god we know that loneliness can
产生如此严重的后果
have such serious consequences
就像吸烟和饮酒一样，
just like smoking and alcohol
尼古丁摄入和饮酒
nicotine consumption and alcohol
consumption
孤独
loneliness is just as big of a health
threat
与吸烟糖尿病污染等健康威胁一样大，
from smoking diabetes pollution etc is
可能是 35
maybe 35 40
40 另一个种族 因
the other race of an early death from
孤独而早逝的比例
loneliness is something like 45 percent
大约为 45%，这几乎是一个
and that's almost a that's almost a
全球性的大流行病，但
global pandemic in its own right but
没有 身体真正醒悟
nobody's really woken up to the fact
到孤独的人得不到的是
that what lonely people don't get is
触摸
touch
问候
hello
视频通话可以给我们一种
video calls can give us a sense of
与家人和朋友的亲近感，
closeness to family and friends
但它们不能取代身体上的
but they cannot replace physical
亲近
proximity
我们中的许多人现在已经意识到这一点
many of us have now become aware of this
[笑声
[Laughter]
] 大流行的
before the pandemic
广告中满是快乐的人在
commercials were full of happy people in
平板电脑
front of tablets
前在镜头前
in front of cameras
互相挥手
waving to each other
问候他们在全球各地的亲人
greeting their loved ones around the
globe
everyone was content and happy
自大流行以来每个人都感到满足和快乐
since the pandemic
我们都不得不依靠我们的数字
we've all had to rely on our digital
设备
devices
窥视一些小东西 相机
peering into some little camera doing
尽最大努力平衡我们的工作，同时仍然
our best to balance our work while still
保持我们的社交生活
keeping our social lives going
我们中的大多数人几乎 90%
and the majority of us almost 90 percent
对这种类型的交流非常不满意
are incredibly unhappy with this type of
communication
如果将来
what would it be like if in the future
我们也可以在
we could also touch each other in the
虚拟世界中相互接触会是什么样子
virtual world
直到现在，我们的触觉一直
until now our sense of touch has always
被认为过于复杂，无法在
been considered too complex to be
技术上复制
technically replicated
touching over the internet
在这个视频中通过互联网触摸它似乎工作
in this video it seems to work
了一个母亲我 她触摸屏幕
a mother is touching the screen
她的孩子远程感觉到她的触摸
and her child feels her touch remotely
[音乐]
[Music]
西北大学的约翰罗杰斯
john rogers of northwestern university
帮助开发了
helped develop the system
他和他的团队希望使
he and his team want to make long
远距离触摸成为可能的系统
distance touch possible
[音乐]
[Music]
我们试图做的是开发
what we've tried to do is to develop
技术
technologies that are compatible with
与人体兼容的柔软灵活的
the human body soft flexible
皮肤界面平台，您
skin interface platforms that you can
几乎可以将其视为第二
almost think of as a as like a second
skin
层皮肤，可以层压
that can laminate onto different parts
到可能感兴趣的身体不同部位，
of the body that might be of interest
they connect the artificial skin
wirelessly to the computer
当屏幕打开时，它们将人造皮肤无线连接到计算机 触摸小型
when the screen is touched the small
集成电子元件会产生反应
integrated electronic elements react
[音乐]，
[Music]
它们将电流
they convert the electrical currents
转化为压力和振动，
into pressure and vibrations
但人造皮肤无法模拟
but the artificial skin cannot simulate
轻柔的触摸，
gentle touching
但这是朝着正确方向迈出的一步
but it is a step in the right direction
我
that i think replicates the kind of
认为它可以复制
touch that can serve as
您所知道的那种触摸 一种深刻的情感和
you know a deeply sort of emotional and
个人的，
personal
呃，你知道与
uh you know connection with with other
其他人的联系，所以我们会考虑它，呃，
other people so so we think about it uh
你知道在 te 嗯，你知道
you know in terms of um you know adding
增加社交媒体体验的有效值
to the uh social media experience that
也许我们现在正在参与
that maybe we're engaging in right now
其中，目前仅由
which is currently dominated only by
视觉和听觉提示主导，如果你
visual and auditory cues if you were
戴着一个设备，我可以拍拍
wearing a device i would be able to pat
你的肩膀，然后你 将
your shoulder for example and you would
能够感觉到你
be able to to feel that you know in in
real
实时知道他的两名员工展示了
time two of his employees show just how
这些触摸有多明显
noticeable these touches are
一个人在屏幕上画出字母
one draws letters on the screen
他的同事可以感觉到并
his colleague can feel and reproduce
在他的手臂上复制这些字母
them on his arm
这种人造皮肤还没有准备
this artificial skin is not yet ready
好上市
for the market
但是有许多潜在的
but there are a number of potential
应用程序
applications
视频游戏
video games
感觉假肢和互联网
feeling prosthesis and internet
通信
communication
社交媒体是一个
social media is one application that's
很明显的应用程序我
that's sort of obvious to think about i
认为特别是在
think especially in the context of what
我们现在所经历
we're living through right now with with
的大流行和
the pandemic and
某种情况下 远程安全参与呃，它
sort of remote safe engagement uh that
仍然保留着那个，嗯，你知道
still retains that um you know that that
那种基于触摸的交互，而且
that interaction based on touch and and
它真的很难复制，
it's really hard to replicate that and
你不能真的 r 仅
you can't really replicate it just with
video and audio
通过从远处在线发送的视频和音频触摸来复制它，
touches sent online from a distance
他们是否可以为
could they provide a solution for those
那些需要身体接触的
in need of physical contact for example
人提供解决方案，例如对于独居的老年人或异地恋的人
for older people living alone or those
in long distance relationships
至少这可能
at the very least it might be better
比没有接触更好
than no touching at all
这几乎可以取代
but could this ever replace the feeling
我们在面对面接触中所体验到的感觉
we experienced during a face-to-face
encounter
吗？你可以穿上
you may be able to apply
一件夹克，有人可以给你一个
a jacket and somebody can give you a
虚拟的拥抱，这是一个非常有趣的概念，
virtual hug which is quite a fun concept
但我仍然认为这不需要
however i still don't think it takes the
实际接触的地方和
place of actual touch and the
你从拥抱你的人那里得到的强化，你
reinforcement that you get from somebody
和
hugging you and both you enjoying it and
他们都喜欢它，
them they enjoy it as well when it's
hard of heart
当事情变得艰难时，比如在大流行期间，当事情变得艰难时，他们也很享受它，很
when things get tough like during the
pandemic
明显我们真正
it becomes clear that what we are truly
渴望的是 技术
longing for isn't technology
不是我们想要一个真正的人和我们出去
we want a real person who goes out for a
喝啤酒或读诗
beer with us or reads us poetry
[音乐]
[Music]
触摸总是有直接和即时的
touch always has a direct and immediate
效果
effect
它唤起情感
it evokes emotions
[音乐]
[Music]
我们都需要
we all need it
它 这是我们生物构成的基本组成部分，
it's a basic component of our biological
makeup
我们都配备了
we are all equipped with receptors for
轻柔触觉的感受器
gentle touch
[音乐]
[Music]
但每个人的触觉体验都
and yet everyone experiences touch
不同，
differently
我们的文化背景，
experiences our cultural background how
我们如何看待自己和我们的
we perceive ourselves and our current
现状，
situation
所有这些都会影响我们是否以及何时
all this influences whether and when we
喜欢它
like it
[音乐]
[Music]
但习惯也会影响我们的感觉，
but habit also shapes how we feel
我们的拥抱传感器需要
our cuddle sensors need to be trained
regularly
在我们的一生中定期接受训练，
throughout our lives
那些没有被触摸
people who are not touched
或不想被触摸的人
or do not want to be touched
随着时间的推移会发现温柔的爱抚变得不那么愉快
find gentle caressing less pleasant over
time
[音乐
[Music]
] 我们认为
and we think that
如果你被触摸得更少并且 在你的
if you get touched less and less in your
生活中，
life
你越来越想念它，以至于你实际上
you miss it so much that you actually
可能会为此感到难过，你可能
you probably feel sad about it you may
会为此感到沮丧
become depressed about it
这并不好，因为
and that's not good because
你实际上越来越少地欣赏触摸
you actually appreciate the touch less
所以你越来越少地寻求触摸，
and less and so you seek touch less and
less
所以真正地触摸你 必须在
so really for touch you have to have
touch on a
on a
非常有规律的基础上进行接触，
on a basis which is very regular
否则我们往往会失去这些
otherwise we tend to lose these these
信号，这些
signals these interactions and
相互作用需要付出努力 再次强化它们
it takes effort to to reinforce them
again
[音乐]
[Music]
幸运的是，我们的触觉可以
fortunately our sense of touch can
随时恢复
return at any time
它会伴随我们一生，
it stays with us throughout our lives
甚至到老年
even into old age
即使一个
a caress can still reach a person even
人与物质世界几乎没有联系，爱抚仍然可以触及
when they are barely connected to the
physical world
它 它传达了我们的情感 所以迫切
it conveys emotions that we so urgently
需要特别是在生命即将结束时的
need especially towards the end of life
可靠性
reliability
安全
safety
和保障
and security
[音乐]
[Music]
rochelle ackerly 做出了一个非凡的
rochelle ackerly has made a remarkable
发现
discovery
触摸的情况非常有趣，
the case of touch is very interesting
because
因为对于其他感官来说，它们确实
it's true that for the other senses
they
会
diminish
随着时间的推移而减弱，所以随着我们年龄的增长，你会看到
with time and so as we get older you see
不太好你听不太清楚
less well you hear less well
但是对于触摸它似乎有两层
however for touch it seems to have two
layers
所以你所拥有的触摸这就是
so the touch that you have which is what
我们所说的有区别的触摸它
we call discriminative touch it's the
是例如当你伸出
touch for example when you reach out and
手触摸某些东西
touch something with your hands
时会随着年龄的增长而减少的触摸所以
that does decrease with age so
嗯
um
it's every
在你的一生中，例如每隔十年左右，
for example every ten years or so in
你就会失去神经
your life you will lose about five
中大约百分之五的所有触觉纤维，
percent of all the touch fibers in your
nerves
但是我们发现 w 当人们
however what we find is that when people
变老时，
get older
他们更喜欢触摸，他们
they appreciate touch more and they
实际上发现触摸更令人愉悦
actually find touch more pleasurable
[音乐]
[Music]
we often don't realize how strongly
touch affects our mood our health
and our relationships
but we are becoming more and more aware
of it
touch makes us happy
我们的生活
throughout our lives
[音乐]
[Music]
你
you